Lewis W. Douglas papers, 1859-1974 (bulk 1880-1960)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Series IV: Lewis W. Douglas Papers, 1906-1974
  - Subseries X: Investments
    - Oil
      - La Sal Vieja and Pantano Petroleum, Willacy County, Texas (La Sal Vieja area and "Cox Well"). 1950-1953 (Box 480, Folder 2-4)
      - Pantano Petroleum and Investment Company. 1951-1961 (Box 480, Folder 5-7)
      - Pantano Petroleum and Investment Company, taxes, stock certificates. no date (Box 480, Folder 8)
      - Book of Class B Common Stock Certificates. 1952-1953 (Box 481)
      - Calumet Oil Company. 1942-1960 (Box 482, Folder 1-3)
      - Calumet Oil Company, reports and trial balances. 1945-1959 (Box 482, Folder 4)
      - Standard Oil Company of Indiana. 1942 (Box 482, Folder 5)
      - Standard Oil Company of New Jersey. 1943-1949 (Box 482, Folder 6)
      - Superior Oil Company. 1945-1955 (Box 482, Folder 7)
      - Tejon ranch Company. 1912-1971 (Box 482, Folder 8-10)
      - Miscellaneous items on Oil. no date (Box 482, Folder 11)
    - Various
      - Aircraft radio Corporation. 1943-1951 (Box 483, Folder 1)
      - Allis-Chalmers Manufacturing Company. 1942-1944 (Box 483, Folder 2)
      - Bank Stocks (various). 1927-1944 (Box 483, Folder 3)
      - Bank Stocks (Valley National Bank). 1925-1946 (Box 483, Folder 4)
      - Cement Wrapped Pipe Company. 1933-1938 (Box 483, Folder 5)
      - Kingsford Chemical Company. 1957-1961 (Box 483, Folder 6)
      - Merlin Products Corp (formerly M.O. Wilkins Corp.). 1928-1930 (Box 483, Folder 7)
      - Montgomery Ward. 1946-1949 (Box 483, Folder 8)
      - Paramount Pictures Corporation. 1947-1957 (Box 483, Folder 9)
      - Phoenix Company. 1955-1957 (Box 483, Folder 10)
      - Prince charles Highland Development Company (later called The Highland Fund). 1952-1955 (Box 483, Folder 11)
      - Public Utilities. 1945-1969 (Box 483, Folder 12)
      - Republic Flow Metals. 1956 (Box 484, Folder 1)
      - Republic Foil and Metal Mills. 1947-1969 (Box 484, Folder 2)
      - Square D Company. 1944-1947 (Box 484, Folder 3)
      - Teachers Insurance and Annuity Association. 1937-1954 (Box 484, Folder 4)
      - U.S. Bonds. 1935-1953 (Box 484, Folder 5)
      - Weekly publications ( Newsweek). 1953-1961 (Box 484, Folder 6)
      - Zinshar Holding Company. 1935-1954 (Box 484, Folder 7)
      - Miscellaneous Investments. 1925-1958 (Box 484, Folder 8)
      - Miscellaneous correspondence regarding investments. 1926-1973 (Box 484, Folder 9-10)
      - Librairie Polytechnique Ch. Beranger. 1957-1962 (Box 485, Folder 1)
      - Nichols Engineering and Research Corporation. 1943-1972 (Box 485, Folder 2-6)
      - Neptune Meter Company. 1969-1972 (Box 485, Folder 7)
      - Mohave Venture Farms. 1952-1959 (Box 486, Folder 1)
      - River Farms, Inc. 1960-1973 (Box 486, Folder 2)
      - Michigan Sugar Co., Holly Sugar Corp., and American Crystal Sugar Corp. 1964-1968 (Box 486, Folder 3-6)
      - Webb and Knapp. 1958-1971 (Box 486, Folder 7-9)
    - Arthur P. Jacobs Co., Inc.
      - Correspondence. 1959-1973 (Box 487, Folder 1-9)
      - Robert Rae's "Gas Possibilities." 1954 (Box 487, Folder 10)
    - Southerwestern Research & General Investment Company
      - Articles of Incorporation, by-laws, manual, Board of Directors. no date (Box 488, Folder 1)
      - Minutes of meetings. 1960-1965 (Box 488, Folder 2-5)
      - Stockholders. no date (Box 488, Folder 6)
      - Reports to Stockholders. 1961-1967 (Box 488, Folder 7)
      - Applicants (lists of). no date (Box 488, Folder 8)
      - Financial Report and Records (various). no date (Box 488, Folder 9)
      - Miscellaneous Material. no date (Box 488, Folder 10)
      - Correspondence. 1960-1962 (Box 489, Folder 1-8)
      - Correspondence. 1962-1964 (Box 490, Folder 1-9)
      - Correspondence. 1964-1968, 1971 (Box 491, Folder 1-8)
      - Canyon Tours, Inc. (Correspondence). 1962-1965 (Box 492, Folder 1)
      - Canyon Tours, Inc. (miscellaneous material). no date (Box 492, Folder 2)
      - Pipe lines. 1960-1962 (Box 492, Folder 3)
      - Fullerform Continuous Pipe Corporation. 1962-1964 (Box 492, Folder 4-7)
      - Markham Advertising Company, Inc. 1962-1965 (Box 492, Folder 8)
      - Arizona Biochemical Company & Kingsford Company. 1962-1963 (Box 493, Folder 1)
      - Flori Investment Company. 1965 (Box 493, Folder 2)
      - Ludwig Engineering and Science. 1964-1965 (Box 493, Folder 3)
      - Malleable Iron Fittings Company. 1962 (Box 493, Folder 4)
      - Phoenix Special Products. 1962-1965 (Box 493, Folder 5)
      - Security Finance Company. 1962-1964 (Box 493, Folder 6)
      - Transcontinental Investing Corporation. 1963-1964 (Box 493, Folder 7)
      - Tubos de Acero de Mexico, S.A. (TAMSA). 1962-1964 (Box 493, Folder 8)
      - Westgate-California Corporation. 1964 (Box 493, Folder 9)
  - Subseries XI: Banks
    - Chase National Bank (NY and London). 1947-1957 (Box 494, Folder 1)
    - Chemical Bank and Trust Company (NY). 1945-1947 (Box 494, Folder 2)
    - Phoenix National Bank, correspondence. 1924-1943 (Box 494, Folder 3)
    - Phoenix National Bank, statments, notes. no date (Box 494, Folder 4)
    - Phoenix National Bank, safety deposit box. 1926-1935 (Box 494, Folder 5)
    - Valley National Bank (Phoenix, AZ). 1945-1947 (Box 494, Folder 6)
    - riggs National Bank (Washington, D.C.). 1927-1951 (Box 494, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous Banks. 1926-1952 (Box 494, Folder 8)
    - Southern Arizona Bank & Trust Company, Southern Arizona Bank Stock sale. 1947-1956 (Box 495, Folder 1-4)
    - Southern Arizona Bank & Trust Company, correspondence, financial statements. 1949-1953 (Box 496, Folder 1-8)
    - Southern Arizona Bank & Trust Company, correspondence. 1954-1955 (Box 497, Folder 1-9)
    - Southern Arizona Bank & Trust Company, correspondence. 1956-1957 (Box 498, Folder 1-9)
    - Southern Arizona Bank & Trust Company, correspondence. June-October 1957 (Box 499, Folder 1-5)
    - Southern Arizona Bank & Trust Company, correspondence. 1957-1959 (Box 500, Folder 1-8)
    - Southern Arizona Bank & Trust Company, correspondence. 1960-1961 (Box 501, Folder 1-10)
    - Southern Arizona Bank & Trust Company, correspondence. 1962-July 1963 (Box 502, Folder 1-10)
    - Southern Arizona Bank & Trust Company, correspondence. August 1963-1964 (Box 503, Folder 1-11)
    - Southern Arizona Bank & Trust Company, correspondence. 1965 (Box 504, Folder 1-9)
    - Southern Arizona Bank & Trust Company, correspondence. 1966-1968 (Box 505, Folder 1-12)
    - Southern Arizona Bank & Trust Company, correspondence. 1969-1974 (Box 506, Folder 1-10)
    - Southern Arizona Bank & Trust Company, Transamerica Corp. (Insurance Plan). 1957-1958 (Box 507, Folder 1)
    - Southern Arizona Bank & Trust Company, Transamerica Corp. (gifrt for F.N. Belgrano, Jr.). 1958 (Box 507, Folder 2)
    - Southern Arizona Bank & Trust Company, Southern Arizona Bank Building (plans). no date (Box 507, Folder 3)
    - Southern Arizona Bank & Trust Company, Southern Arizona Bank Building (opening, correspondence). March 1, 1958 (Box 507, Folder 4)
    - Southern Arizona Bank & Trust Company, Southern Arizona Bank Building (opening, speech, photos, program, etc). March 1, 1958 (Box 507, Folder 5)
    - Southern Arizona Bank & Trust Company, Bank Holding Company Act (correspondence). 1955-1958 (Box 507, Folder 6-8)
    - Southern Arizona Bank & Trust Company, Bank Holding Company Act (miscellaneous reports). no date (Box 507, Folder 9)
    - Southern Arizona Bank & Trust Company, stock exchange with Transamerica. September 7, 1955 (Box 508, Folder 1)
    - Southern Arizona Bank & Trust Company, legal papers with Transamerica. 1959-1960 (Box 508, Folder 2)
    - Southern Arizona Bank & Trust Company, banking survery. June 1955 (Box 508, Folder 3)
    - Southern Arizona Bank & Trust Company, personnel. 1954-1958 (Box 508, Folder 4)
    - Southern Arizona Bank & Trust Company, comparative data on salaries and fringe benefits. 1956 (Box 508, Folder 5)
    - Southern Arizona Bank & Trust Company, Southwestern Agrochemical Corp. (Ammonia plant in Mexico). 1956-1961 (Box 508, Folder 6)
    - Southern Arizona Bank & Trust Company, miscellaneous material. no date (Box 508, Folder 7)
    - Southern Arizona Bank & Trust Company, trip to Mexico. April 2-7, 1954 (Box 508, Folder 8)
    - Southern Arizona Bank & Trust Company, trip to Mexico. April 13-24, 1955 (Box 508, Folder 9)
    - Southern Arizona Bank & Trust Company, trip to Mexico. 1957 (Box 508, Folder 10)
    - Southern Arizona Bank & Trust Company, Nogales branch. 1954-1960 (Box 508, Folder 11)
    - Southern Arizona Bank & Trust Company, Mexican banking. 1962-1973 (Box 509, Folder 1-3)
    - Southern Arizona Bank & Trust Company, Indian economic development. 1965-1970 (Box 509, Folder 4-6)
    - Southern Arizona Bank & Trust Company, Banker's Forum (Georgetown University, Washington, D.C.). 1963, 1965, 1966 (Box 509, Folder 7-9)
    - Southern Arizona Bank & Trust Company, Anaconda Company. 1964-1968 (Box 509, Folder 10)
    - Southern Arizona Bank & Trust Company, Deltec International, Ltd. (Swift de la Plata, Argentina). 1971-1974 (Box 509, Folder 11)
    - Southern Arizona Bank & Trust Company, personnel, Richard E. Crane. 1964-1970 (Box 509, Folder 12)
    - Southern Arizona Bank & Trust Company, articles of incorporation. 1903 (1964 copy) (Box 510, Folder 1)
    - Southern Arizona Bank & Trust Company, histories of SAB, photographs. no date (Box 510, Folder 2)
    - Southern Arizona Bank & Trust Company, art purchases. 1953-1972 (Box 510, Folder 3)
    - Southern Arizona Bank & Trust Company, stockholder lists. 1955-1956 (Box 510, Folder 4)
    - Southern Arizona Bank & Trust Company, plans for merger with First National Bank of Arizona. 1972 (Box 510, Folder 5)
    - Southern Arizona Bank & Trust Company, Vincent V. Lisica (Swiss banking interests). 1964-1964 (Box 510, Folder 6)
  - Subseries XII: Oversize material
    - 6th Arizona State Legislature (Colorado River). 1923-1924 (Box 511, Folder 1)
    - Political Campaign. 1926 (Box 511, Folder 2)
    - 70th congress (legislation: Farm Relief & Colorado River). no date (Box 511, Folder 3)
    - Political Campaign. 1928 (Box 511, Folder 4)
    - 71st Congress (legislation: Colorado River, Boulder Dam, Public Lands). no date (Box 511, Folder 5)
    - 71st Congress (legislation: Prohibition). no date (Box 511, Folder 6)
    - 71st Congress (legislation: LWD's bill H.R. 8286) (Box 511, Folder 7)
    - Political Campaign. 1930 (Box 511, Folder 8)
    - 72nd Congress (legislation: Copper Tariff). no date (Box 511, Folder 9)
    - 72nd Congress (legislation: various). no date (Box 511, Folder 10)
    - 72nd Congress ("Economy File"). no date (Box 511, Folder 11)
    - Political Campaign. 1932 (Box 511, Folder 12)
    - "Family Tree." no date (Box 512)
    - LWD's desk blotter (gift from his wife). no date (Box 512)
    - Photographs of LWD. no date (Box 512, Folder 1)
    - Mutual Life Insurance Company, Money News. June 29, 1959 (Box 512, Folder 2)
    - General Motors, photograph of the Board of Directors. no date (Box 512, Folder 3)
    - Douglas Memorial Window (Montreal) photographs. no date (Box 512, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous items. 1930-1956 (Box 512, Folder 5)
    - Directory of the Budget (various clippings). no date (Box 512, Folder 6)
    - "Democrats for Willkie" and Committee to Defend America (clippings). no date (Box 512, Folder 7)
    - Ambassador. 1947-1950 (Box 512, Folder 8)
    - Awards and Memberships. 1934-1964 (Box 512, Folder 9)
    - Southern Arizona Bank & Trust Company. 1956-1970 (Box 512, Folder 10)
    - Verde Exploration, Ltd. (maps relating to Paul A. Handverger's reports). 1964-1968 (Box 512, Folder 11)
    - Two volumes of The Graphic (London) about Queen Victoria, inscribed to LWD from his grand-aunts Libbie and Kate Douglas. April 3, 1901 (Box 512)
  - Subseries XIII: Records and Tape
    - 2 Records: Unveiling of Roosevelt Memorial Statue, Grosvenor Square, London by Mrs. F.D. Roosevelt. April 12, 1948 (Box 513)
    - 2 Records: "Tucson Speech." November 1940 (Box 513)
    - 1 Tape: Pima County Democratic Committee & Young Democrats Clubs of Arizona, Jefferson-Jackson Day Dinner, Tucson, AZ. May 3, 1952 (Box 513)
  - Subseries XIV: Film
    - "John J. McCloy," Presented by Lewis W. Douglas. Chase Manhattan Bank's Director's Dinner. December 21, 1960 (Box 514)